是我 我知道你不想跟我共处一室
It's me. i know you can't stand to see me.
我想用电话跟你道歉
I'm trying to apologize over the phone--
我不该亲你的女朋友
I shouldn't have kissed your girlfriend--
别再打来了
Stop calling!
这里是92.3摇滚广播电台
This is 92.3 WXRK, K-Rock...
您是今天的千元挑战者
...calling with our $ 1000 daily challenge!
太好了
All right!
愿意为你做任何事的室友叫什么名字
... your roommate who is very sorry and would do anything
8小时
Eight hours.
你应该用得上入耳式的手机耳机吧
You could probably use a plug-in telephone headset.
我们会收到 你从公司偷来的圣诞礼物吗
Should we all expect christmas gifts that are stolen f santa, you know
你不会
You shouldn't.
讲到圣诞节
Speaking of Christmas
莫妮卡和我刚开业  没有钱
Since Monica and I are starting a new business and have no money
今年就用  秘密圣诞老人的方法抽签互送吧
...this year we could do secret santa and each on santa, you know
这样只要买一份礼物  还可以猜猜看谁抽到谁
And there's the added mystery of who gets who.
谁抽到  哪个人
Who gets whom.
我不知道我为什么这么做
I don't know why I do that.
我得睡一会儿了  火鸡让我好困
I'm going to take a nap. turkey makes me sleepy.
我们还没吃呢
We haven't eaten yet.
我知道  但你们所作的
I know, but all that work you're
得有一会儿了
doing to get itabout to start
你们有人抽到瑞秋吗  我要换
Did you pick rachel for your secret santa? l'lry gift she gets
我抽到她  幸好你要她
I picked her. Thank God, you want her!
你为什么这么想换掉她
Why do you want to get rid of her so badly?
因为她收到什么都拿去换
She exchanges every gift she gets. something she likes.
要让她满意根本不可能
It's impossible to get her
来换吧
Come on, let's trade!
哪有这回事 她很喜欢我送她的背包
I got her that backpack and she loved it.
有只大狗把它叼走时 她哭得好
I remember she cried when that big dog ran off with--
没有什么大狗
There was no big dog.
太讨厌了
This sucks!
我已经为她买了个包还拿去烫了RG
I already got her a briefcase with "R.G. " put on it.
她的姓名缩写
Her initials.
你可以送别人啊  像罗斯盖勒
Maybe you can give it to somebody else. like ross geller!
那是个女用公事包
You know what? It's a girlie briefcase.
那又怎样  他在博物馆上班
Who cares! He works in a museum.
现在几点  球赛要开始了
The big game's about to start!
不必装了 罗斯乔伊不在
Ross and Joey aren't here.
你可以看游行 谢了
You can watch the parade. watch the parador is richard!
谢谢
Thanks.
这个冰箱怎么搞的
What is wrong with this freezer?
怎么了   我的眼睛被冰扎到
-What happened? -Ice just got in my eye!
这里有人要睡觉
People are trying to sleep in here!
莫妮卡的眼睛被冰扎到很痛
Monica got ice in her eye and it hurts!
张开让我看看 不行  真的很痛
-Open it up. Let me see. -I can't. It really kills.
也许你应该冰敷
Maybe you should put some ice on it.
-好像很严重  -去看医生好了
-It looks bad. -We should take you to a doctor.
不行  我的眼科医生是理查
No, my eye doctor is Richard!
我没有男朋友不能去见他
I can't go to him when I don't have a boyfriend.
他对他的病人还真挑剔
He's really picky about his patients.
你非去不可 他的诊所电话几号
You've got to go. What's his office number?
我哪会记得
Like I remember his office number!
速拨键七
Speed dial seven.
我代表莫妮卡盖勒的眼睛
I'm calling on behalf of Monica Geller's eye.
理查柏克今天在吗
Is Richard Burke in today?
他不在  她愿意看候诊医师吗
He's not in. Will she see the on-call doctor?
愿意  愿意  她非常兴奋
She's very excited about that!
酷毙了 莫妮卡回来之前  我是主厨
It's so cool. Till Monica gets back, I'm head chef.
我可以做决定
And I get to make all the decisions.
她叫你完全照食谱来
She told you to follow the recipe exactly.
滚出我的厨房
Get out of my kitchen.
好  我跟乔伊有进展了
I think I'm making some progress with Joey.
我进门时  他走进他的房间
When l walked in, he went to his bedroom...
但只摔了一次门
...but he only slammed the door once.
不过摔的时候有对我竖中指
Yeah, he gave me the finger while doing it.
我得问我妈左手烹饪的问题
I've got to call my mom and ask her a left-handed cos over there.
我抽到莫妮卡
I picked Monica for Secret Santa,
但我已经替她买了光明节礼物 你想换吗
but I'm getting her something for Hanukkah.You want to switch?
其实我想换成你
I was trying to trade . . .for you.
真的  真好  你要送我什么
Really? That's so nice. What are you getting me?
不晓得  RG 某种女性化的上班用品吧
I don't know, R.G. I was thinking something girlie for your office.
也许菲比会跟我换
Maybe Phoebe will switch with me.
最好不要  那你会抽到瑞秋
Then you'll get stuck with rachel,
她什么礼物都拿去换
and she exchangis over there.
乱讲 我送她很多东西她都没退
No, I got her lots of stuff she never took back.
像什么
Like?
像我去年送她的金项链
Like that gold necklace I got her last year.
她上次戴是什么时候
When did she wear it last?
她圣诞节整天都戴着  然后
She wore it all Christmas day and then
大狗
Big dog?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
把钱德勒因内疚买的东西退回去
Sending back this stuff Chandler bought.
全部  包括电视
Even the Tv?
不  电视要搬进我房里
No, I'll put that in my room.
乔伊  我知道他做错了
Listen, Joey. I know what he did was wrong.
但你就不能听他解释吗
But can't you hear him out?
话说回来  当你和瑞秋在一起时
If Chandler had kissed Rachel,
要是钱德勒吻了她 你会听他解释吗
would you hear him out?
说得好
That's a good point.
那你要罚他多久   5年
How long you going to punish him? Five years. Five years.
你还判了刑
You've sentenced him?
不敢当就不要做
Don't do the crime if you can't do the time.
他是你最要好的朋友
The guy's your best friend.
那是以前
Was my best friend.
你干嘛拼命替他说情
I don't know why you're pushing for him.
少了他碍事
With him out of the way as my
我就没有最要好的朋友了
best friend, their spot open.
我吗   对
Who, me?
我真荣幸 你知道我作为朋友首先要做什么
I'm honored. You know what I'm going to do as your best friend?
拉你去跟钱德勒说话
I'm going to get you to talk to Chandler.
好啦
All right.
若非你是我最好的朋友
But if you weren't my best friend
天哪  真的那么严重
Oh, my God. Is it really that bad?
我进了门  他根本不理我
I walk in the room, and he won't talk to me.
只念了几句意大利文
He just mumbles something in ltalian.
我知道他只会脏话
And I know he only knows the bad words.
甘瑟  你有看见钱德勒吗
Gunther, have you seen chandler?
我一直以为你是钱德勒
-l thought you is over there.
你们其中一个在那边
But one of you is over there.
乔伊
Hey, joe.
我马上就好 谢谢你们的到来
I'll be right with you. Thanks for coming in.
天哪  这个候诊医生真帅
Oh, my God! How cute is the on-call doctor?
帅到我想拿笔插我的眼睛
So cute that I'm thinking about jamming this pen in my eye.
柏克医生帮你看
Dr. burke will see you now.
不是柏克医生  他不在
Not Dr. Burke. he is out of town
是候诊医生要帮我看
the on call doctor will see me
理查柏克医生不在
Dr. Richard Burke is out.
他儿子提摩西柏克医生帮你看
Dr. Timothy Burke, his son, will see you now.
准备好了吗
Ready?
对不起  刚才
Hey, I'm sorry. That
你要去哪里   我爸妈家
-Where you going? -My folks' .
什么时候回来
When you coming back?
不知道 可能会住几天顺便找房子
I don't know. I might stay there while I look for an apartment.
什么
What?
原先我以为我们可以谈开来
I thought we could talk about this. work it out.
但是看到你们在一起  我不认为
Seeing you two together, l don't....
你要我说什么   说我不见她吗
What do you want me to say? should l stop seeing her?
跟她无关  好吗
It's not about her. okay?
但看到你们在一起 就让我想起你做的事
But seeing you together reminds me of what you did.
我不跟一个不懂朋友道义的人 住在一起
I won't live with someone who doesn't to be a friend
我懂朋友道义  只是我搞砸了
I know what it is to be a friend. l screwed up.
对  没错
Yeah, you did.
所以我要离开
And that's why l'm leaving.
你不为我留下来  至少为它们留下来
If you're not going to stay for me,then at least stay for them.
它们这1年很不顺
They had a very difficult year.
还被抢
what with the ras robbing us..
当那个人抢了我们
When that guy was robbing us...
我在柜子里关了6小时
...and l was locked in the entertainment
你知道我在做什么
...do you know what l was doing?
我在想我太让你失望了
I was thinking about how l let you down.
早知道你会见色忘友
If l knew what kind of friend you'd
我根本不会担心 再见
be, l wouldn'td that unit...
等一下一定有什么我能做的
Wait one second! there has to be something that l can do.
如果柜子还在
If we still had that unit...
我会关6小时
...l'd get in it for six hours and
检讨我有多让你失望
think about how ent patient.
怎么了
What?
我们有一个箱子
We got a box.
我记得上次见到你
I remember the last time I saw you.
是去上大学的早上
It was the morning l left for college.
你站在奶品皇后乳品店外面
You were standing outside the Dairy Queen
八成是在等它开店
Just probably waiting for it to open.
你现在好漂亮 你也很帅
You look great now. You look great too.
你真是个好病人
You're an excellent patient.
情况如何
How does it look?
你的角膜有刮伤 得戴几天眼罩
You have a scratch on your cornea. You have to wear a patch.
像海盗那样
Like a pirate?
如果你非要这么说的话
If that helps you.
你跟着你爸多久了
How long have you been working with your dad?
总得有人提到他
Come on, one of us had to mention him.
我是2个月前搬回来的
I moved back here a couple months ago.
晚上要家庭聚餐
Big family dinner tonight?
不会吧
No way!
我本来要去女朋友家过感恩节的
I was gonna have thanksgiving at my girlfriend's.
但我们分手了
But we broke up.
她还不想定下来
She wasn't ready for a serious commitment.
所以你把她推下海了  是吧  水手
So you made her walk the plank, aye, matey?
你还没戴眼罩呢
You're not wearing the patch yet.
我知道
I know.
-他要来过感恩节  -对啊  好变态喔
-he's coming here for thanksgiving? -l know. lt's sick.
-为什么变态   -因为他是理查的儿子
-why is it sick? -lt's richard's son!
这跟找希腊悲剧来吃饭一样
It's like inviting a greek tragedy over for dinner.
菲比  你了解吧
Phoebe, you understand, don't you?
我知道你为什么拿我当挡箭牌 但是不行
I could see where l'd be your best shot, but no.
对不起  我觉得很畸形
Sorry, honey. l think it's twisted.
-什么事畸形   -我跟理查的儿子交往
-what's twisted? -me going out with richard's son.
我觉得实在不太好
It sounds like a really bad idea to me.
-他这样可以吗   -他好得很
-Is he okay in there? -He's fine!
要是你跟理查的儿子有结果
If things work out between you and richard's son...
你就可以告诉孩子
...you can tell your kids...
你跟他们的爷爷上过床
...that you slept with their grandfather.
随你们怎么批评
Judge all you want to.
娶到女同志  临阵逃婚
Married a lesbian, left a man at the altar...
爱上同性恋冰上舞者
...loved a gay ice dancer...
把女生的木腿丢进火里 关在箱子里
...threw a girl's wooden leg in the fire, live in a box!
-关箱子的用意到底何在   -钱德勒
-What exactly is the point of the box? -Chandler
有三重意义
The meaning of the box is threefold.
第一  让我有时间反省
One, it gives me the time to think about what l did.
第二  证明我有多重视 跟乔伊的友谊
Two, it proves how much I care about my friendship with Joey.
第三会痛
And three... ...it hurts.
记得我去年送你的项链吗
Remember that necklace l gave you last year?
可以给我看吗
Can l see it?
为啥
Why?
我只是想看一下
I just want to check something.
好吧
Okay.
等着瞧吧
Now we'll see.
气孔  气孔
Air hole! air hole!
在这里  我很喜欢  我常戴
Here it is. l love it. l wear it all the time.
我送的是金项链  这是银的
The necklace l got you was gold. this is silver.
也许它变了
Well, maybe... ...it changed.
天哪  你真的拿去换
Oh, my god! you actually exchanged it.
换一个我喜欢又常用的东西
Isn't it better to exchange it for something l enjoy...
不是更有用吗
...and can use a lot?
你换了什么
What did you get?
存款
Credit.
我来开我来开
I'll get it. l'll get it. l'll get
我来迎接帅哥
it. l'll get ithat wizard guy
提姆
Hi, tim.
谢谢  来见我的朋友
Thank you. come meet my friends.
这是菲比 幸会
Phoebe.
乔伊 你好
And joey.
我哥哥罗斯 你好
My brother, ross.
还有瑞秋
And rachel.
那是钱德勒 你好
That's chandler.
你好啊
How do you do?
-这是 -他在
-what's--? -well, he's....
他在反省
He's doing some thinking.
-怎么了   -你亲了我的女朋友
-what happened? -you kissed my girlfriend!
我喜欢那个墨镜
I like those sunglasses.
是喜欢的喜欢
''like them'' like them? or ''l'd
还是可以换成存款的喜欢
like to get store credit" Iike them?
各位  火鸡上桌了
This turkey is ready.
哪里可以洗手
Where can I wash up?
来我带你去
Iet me show you.
毛巾挂在洗手台旁边
The towels are hanging next to the sink.
-你可以用高级香皂  -谢谢
-and you can use the fancy soap. -thank you.
高级香皂   我以为要留给教皇用
Fancy soap? l thought we were saving that for the pope.
他人很好吧
See. he's nice, right?
但你真的想在谈恋爱时说
Yeah right, but monica. Do you want a relationship where you can actually use the phase:
你爸爸也这么做过
''that's not how your dad used to do it''?
看起来好好吃  我坐哪里
Everything looks great. where should l sit?
我帮你留了
Saved you a seat.
变态变态变态变态
Sick, sick, sick, sick.
我去开
I'll get it.
骗到你了
Got you!
这听起来不像是反省
That doesn't sound like thinking to me.
-抱歉  -你不应该说话
-sorry! -you shouldn't be talking at all.
你要想的太多了  不该说话开玩笑
You've got too much thinking to do to be talking and joking.
好  没问题
Okay, you got it!
罗斯  把蕃薯给我
Ross, pass me the yams?
好  你想换的话 乔伊那里有马铃薯泥
Joey's got the mashed potatoes if you want to exchange them.
够了  你是怎么搞的
Will you stop! what's the matter with you?
有客人喔
We've got company.
我没怎么搞的
Nothing's the matter with me.
我不是麻木不仁的人 我也有感觉
I'm not completely devoid of sentiment. l have feelings.
好  很好
Okay, fine.
你们看不到 但我正在露屁股打圆场
You can't tell, but I'm breaking the tension by mooning you guys.
听着
All right, look!
如果你把它当成笑话 那就算了
If this is a big joke to you, forget about it.
这对我很重要
This means something to me.
要是对你不重要  你就滚出来
If it doesn't mean anything to you, then get out of there.
否则你就是待在箱子里的白痴
Otherwise, you're just an idiot in a box.
你说得对  对不起  这对我非常重要
You're right. l'm sorry. this means a lot to me.
我想跟你和解
I want to be friends again. l
我发誓不会再说话了
swear l won't sa this is weird.
-你会当一回事  -绝对会
-so you'll take this seriously? -absolutely!
你又说话啰
That sounds like another word to me.
你会当一回事吗
Are you going to take this seriously?
很好
Okay!
别说我麻木不仁
Don't say that l have no sentiment.
这是第一次约会的电影票根
This is a movie stub from our first date.
这是你第一次 为我做床上早餐的蛋壳
This eggshell is from the first time you made me breakfast in bed.
这是博物馆的  我们第一次
This is from the museum, the first time we
在一起
were together.
我有时会换礼物
Maybe I exchange gifts sometimes,
但重要的东西我会留
but I keep the things that matter.
我不知道该说什么  对不起
I don't know what to say. l'm sorry.
但是这个不能拿
Though you're not supposed to take these.
它有百万年的历史
It's, like, a million years old.
我们还得派专人去挖
We actually have people looking for that.
总是这样
This always happens.
我来帮你
Here, let me.
谢谢
Thank you.
你有好美
You have very beautiful...
的眼睛
...eye.
我朋友都觉得太奇怪了
My friends think this is weird.
我原先也觉得会
I thought it would be. l almost
这样不会很怪吧
canceled, but i that not okay?
我原先也觉得会  还差点取消 但其实不会
I know. me and your dad, that's totally separate.
我知道
I totally agree.
我跟你爸完全是两回事 我完全同意
We're two people who find each other...
我们只是两个互相吸引的人 对吧
...very attractive. Right?
-怎么了   -没事
-what? -nothing, nothing.
那个吻不好吗
No, really. was that not okay?
不  很好
No, that was good.
那个吻很好
That was a good kiss.
-天哪  它让你想到  -别说
-lt reminded you of-- -don't say it!
-但是有  对吧  -对
-lt did, didn't it? -yes!
天哪  我知道
I know!
-听着  我真的很抱歉  -没关系
-l want you to know how sorry l am-- -lt's okay.
-我气的是钱德勒  -抱歉
-chandler's the one l'm mad at. -well, l'm still sorry.
-他在吗  -在箱子里
-ls he here? -ln the box.
-钱德勒   -他现在不能说话
-Chandler -He can't talk right now.
为什么  怎么了
Why not? what's going on?
他想表示他很重视乔伊
He's trying to show joey how much he means to him.
-所以窝在箱子里   -乔伊有他的理由
-by being in a box? -joey had reasons.
有三重意义
They were threefold.
你不能说话反而让事情好办
You not being able to talk might make this easier.
听我说
Listen
我不想介入
I don't want to be someone who
两个最要好的朋友
comes between two best friends.
我不忍心看着这件事影响你们
I can't stand seeing what this is doing to you guys.
我不想成为罪魁祸首
And l don't want to be the cause of that.
所以我们不该再见面了
I don't think we can see each other anymore.
我要去芝加哥找我妈
I'm going to my mom's in chicago.
我会住一阵子
I'm going to stay there for a while.
这段感情本来会很美好
I think this could have been something really amazing.
但这么做也许最好
But, you know, this is probably for the best.
你懂吗
You know?
我会想你的
I'm going to miss you.
别了  钱德勒
Goodbye, chandler.
把箱子打开啦
Open the box!
什么
What?
他还追得上她  快出来啦
He can still catch her. get out of there! get out of there!
-所以 -我们没事啦  出来啦
-So -We're going to be fine. get out!
真的  对  你好好反省过了
You did some real good thinking in there.
这真是
I mean, this is....
快  你还追得上她
You could still catch her!
神秘圣诞老人祝你圣诞快乐
And merry christmas from your secret santa!
谁抽到钱德勒  我要换
All right, who got chandler? because l need to trade.
他看到她了
He sees her!
他在追她
He's catching up to her.
她看到他了
She sees him!
他们拥抱了
They're hugging!
他在抢她的皮包
He's taking her purse.
那不是他们
That's not them.
我去报警
I'll go call the police.
他们在那里
There they are!
快去开房间吧
All right, get a room.